# OLEKSANDR BODNARASHYK

PROGRAMMER, SYSTEMS ANALYST

boda2004@gmail.com skype: a.bodnarashik GitHub account Upwork account IRC: boda@RusNet

# Objective

I'd like to take part in projects, which require strong knowledge of sites building principles and UI/UX guidelines for handheld device applications. Also I'm keen on systems, capable to provide high reliability, availability, and

serviceability (RAS).

Want to be on bleeding edge, apply modern techniques, libraries and frameworks to achieve the best result.

My hourly rate starts from \$20/hr.

# Personal Data

Name: Oleksandr Surname: Bodnarashyk Date of birth: 06/Mar/1982

Age: 33

Languages: Ukrainian, Russian, English

Place of birth: Ukraine

## Skills

# **Programming**

Produce code of high quality in different programming languages, using vast number of frameworks and libraries where applicable.

## Security

Good knowledge in areas of computer security, networks, distributed systems.

# **Project Direction**

Proven ability to lead and manage a wide variety of development projects in team and independent situations.

# **Technical**

HTML5 / xHTML	jQuery	Android
React / Flux / Redux	Bootstrap	Java
AngularJS	Git / Mercurial	Nginx / Apache / Tomcat
Cordova / ionic	PHP	Windows
Symfony2	MySQL	OSX
CSS2.1 / CSS3	Node.js	FreeBSD
Javascript / ECMAScript	C / C++ / Objective-C	Linux

# Experience

## Freelancer

Software Engineer

Developing Web sites and native applications for handheld devices.

Platform: Android, Java, Tomcat, nginx, nodejs. Language: java/php/mysql/javascript/etc. February 2014 - Present

### Senior Developer, Technical Lead

Developing offportal applications for handheld devices and server interface.

Platform: iOS, J2ME, BlackBerry, Android, JavaSE, Tomcat, nginx.

Language: java/objective-c/php/mysql/etc.

## CDAS

October 2006 - June 2009

#### Software Engineer

Content providing wap sites developing.

Platform: independent.

Language: php/perl/mysql/(x)html/chtml/wml etc.

WAP3 LTD 2005-2006

#### Software Engineer

Content providing wap sites developing. Responsible for frontend, developing API, new features, statistics gathering and analysis programs, automatic email composition and delivery. Temporary responsible for projects of content department.

Platform: independent.

Language: php/perl/mysql/(x)html/chtml/wml etc.

# Employer - Businessman

2004-2005

## Software Engineer

Content providing wap sites developing. Responsible for frontend, developing API, new features.

Platform: independent.

Language: php/perl/mysql/(x)html/chtml/wml etc.

## Freelancer

1999-1999(less than a year)

# Software Engineer

Taking part in developing plugins for video rendering software (Aist MoviePack).

Platform: MS-Windows.

Language: C/C++.

# Education

# Zhytomyr State Technological University

2003-2004

Master degree in computer science

# Zhytomyr State Technological University

1999-2003

Bachelor in computer science, Zhytomyr State Technological University

# Portfolio

# **HashTag**

Allows early participants to subscribe and be notified about upcoming event. Implemented markup and functionality (design and gfx was provided by customer).



#### Highlights

- Full Symfony2 application stack
- · Admin backend (Sonata Admin bundle)
- Referral system
- Sharing via Facebook
- CSS 3d transformations with graceful degradation for unsupported browsers

# Powerchat - Worldwide Chat

Took part in project as a tech lead. Integrated websockets into application for instant chat. Implemented protocol on server side. Submitted various fixes.

## Highlights

- Android
- Client side cache (images, data)
- InApp purchases



## **IWD POS System**

iPad application to automate credit card information input on sites. (Application logo was provided by customer).



#### Highlights

- iOS
- · Support for various UniMag magnetic stripe readers
- · Automatic scanner activation on pages, marked as containing credit card information form

# **Power Chat VIP**

Took part in project as a developer. Area of responsibility: protocol implementation (client and server endpoints), backend core, client model.

#### Highlights

- ios
- Client side cache (images, data)

#### <u>Sparta</u>

Merchandiser application to ease and automate their job. Implemented Android application. Implemented most part of server side model and mobile frontend.



#### Highlights

- Android/PHP
- Symfony2
- AngularJS
- · Client side caching
- · Photo capturing
- · GPS tracking
- Single page application
- · Offline mode support

## **Beyond The Sea**

Personal blog. Implemented backend (design and gfx was provided by customer, markup and javascript implemented by other team member).



## Highlights

- · Custom blog engine
- Own template engine

## Secret Altar

Virtual online exhibition. Implemented/composed xml/xsl files and server side transformation (design and gfx was provided by customer).



# Highlights

- · Client side XSLT with server side transformation for unsupported browsers
- JavaScript animations (jQuery based)

# Pukka Names

Lets people to pick up their site name. Implemented markup and functionality (design, gfx and database was provided by customer).



## Highlights

- Ajaxified
- Used jQuery plugins (validation, scroll)
- CSV backed database

There is a plenty of other projects which are not listed here for various reasons, e.g.

- · They duplicate features/functionality of already mentioned
- I've forgotten about them or have no links/code samples
- NDA
- I feel ashamed of them



# Summary

I'm responsible and highly motivated person. I pay a lot of attention to internals of product, not to only look&feel, hope it makes products I've created more robust and stable. I'm a quick learner, so require less time to get into problem and fix it. I like to solve complex issues and happy if I make it in some elegant way. My experience lets me to play different roles in project and gives me understanding of consumers, customers and developers needs.

 $Oleks and r \ Bodnarashyk - \underline{boda2004@gmail.com}$